TOLULOPE AMAO

Email: adeyemiamao@gmail.com; Portfolio: https://linktr.ee/deyemigram Phone: +234 905 759 9717 Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/amao-tolulope-ux-designer-program-manager

A product designer and webflow developer with a proven track record of shaping ideas into intuitive product solutions and driving a user-centered approach to boost user experience and customer satisfaction. I have experience building products people love across various industries, including fashion, web3, fintech, industrial manufacturing, and HRTech. When I'm not designing, I'm either reading design articles on Medium or exploring the discovery feature on Spotify.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BizTapp, Germany

March 2023 - Present

Product Designer (Contract)

- By incorporating cutting-edge industry trends and utilizing insights obtained from conducted interviews, I redesign the admin section using Figma to further simplify the user interface and provide a seamless and contemporary UX, which results in an increase in adoption rate and customer satisfaction by 25%.
- Create and own the UX strategy for the growth team and partner with product and engineering peers to ensure that designs and solutions meet user, technical and business needs.
- Present and communicate the overall design workflow to team members and stakeholders.

Hearverse, UAE

June 2023 – August 2023

Product Designer (Freelance)

- Drove the entire workflow, from concept to wireframing to prototyping and high-fidelity design, working closely with the rest of the product and engineering (developers) team on execution.
- Created wireframes, prototypes, and mock-ups to showcase layout options, ensuring seamless navigation and a compelling user experience.
- Advocated for new design trend that matches web3 industry standards and web accessibility, and making sure the user experience was considered a top priority with respect to the age bracket this product is meant to cater for.

Asiga Printer, Australia

July 2023 – August 2023

Product Designer (Contract)

• Designed and prototyped the user interface for the new DLP 3D printer, ensuring adherence to accessibility standards.

Billed, Nigeria

May 2021 – February 2023

Product Designer

- Led the design team of two designers to drive discovery and support the evolving design process to prioritize, build, and ship new features that boost customer satisfaction by 20%.
- Estimated the design effort required, tracking OKRs, and measuring how experience impacts our users by Collaborate with cross-functional teams to understand user behavior and requirements, translating them into effective design solutions
- Advocated for the value of user-centered design within the organization to offer a competitive advantage and improve usability and efficiency by 25%.
- Integrated and facilitated data driven feedback throughout the design process, leveraging surveys, user testing, interviews, ethnographic studies, and user data to measure feature performance in the app, which led to an increase in user adoption rates of up to 18%.

Product Designer and Webflow Developer (Freelance)

- Designed and annotated design concepts such as storyboards, sitemaps, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes, encompassing more than 20 screens for both web and mobile applications. Documented these designs to facilitate development.
- Developed website that met accessibility standards, followed established design systems, and presented visual elements with a focus on readability, comprehension, and easy information retrieval.
- Developed a competitor study to give the client's product a competitive advantage over 15 different competitors.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Agriculture, Abeokuta,

January 2015 - October 2019

BSc. Mathematics

National Open University of Nigeria,

September 2023- April 2024

PGD. Information Technology

SKILLS

Design Thinking, Information Architecture, User Experience (UX) Research, Usability Testing, Prototyping, Wireframing, Agile Development, Documentation, Visual Design, Attention to Detail, and Webflow Development, SEO optimization, referral systems, gamification and conversion rate improvement

TOOLS

Figma, Webflow, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Framer, HTML/CSS, Miro, Jitter and Jira

CERTIFICATIONS

Google UX Design Specialization: Coursera,

May 2022

Product Design: Udacity

December 2021

Google Product Management Course: Coursera,

December 2022